In our modern societies nowadays, agriculture has no exception to cope with modern technologies, from crops monitoring to cultivation, all are technologically integrated. Back in 1960s, soil plowing activity was done by using both human and buffalo plowing the soil with custom-made 'vehicle'. With advancement in embedded system especially robotics, the same task can be done faster without a need for rest in between tasks and without any intervention by human/animal. This project involves in creating such application by using a mini prototype of mobile robot that is moving autonomously in a grid manner with self-coordination of its location. The robot is utilising the latest Bluetooth version 4.0 module or simply called Bluetooth SmartTM or Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) wireless technology that is very low energy consumption, hence prolong the system lifespan and able to directly communicate with smartphone to update its location to the user. The robot is also pre-programmed with an algorithm to detect any surrounding obstacles and respond to provide with necessary action. The above-said module is located at 2 different fixed points in a rectangle shape to act as an access points for the robot to locate itself. The final outcome is that the robot can self-locate itself to move line by line in a grid topology map of the crops' field. 
